OROPO'S TOWER
Flopin?
Flopin!
I'm right here, Mama. Mama!
I'm over here.
I noticed something really weird about
these things. Watch what they do.
-My cuts have disappeared.
-That's not all.
I've spent hours checking our cell.
It's open,
but there's no way to escape
and the walls are slippery,
so you can't grip them.
You're right, there's no way to escape,
anywhere.
At least for now.
-We're going to find a way out of here.
-Sure you will!
That is, if I leave you enough time.
Mama, it's that crazy lady's voice,
the Sram who attacked us!
Toxine!
Don't let your guard down. We'll...
Fall!
We're finally here.
I don't understand.
I can't feel anything.
These plants have no signs of life.
We'll pick flowers later.
There's a pretty girl to rescue!
And an annoying brother, too!
Best of all, there's a fight to be had!
Elely, hold on!
Well, it didn't take us very long
to fall into a trap.
It's a temporal bubble. We need
to move fast before they find us.
We're too vulnerable like this.
Let's go to the entrance.
I can barely move.
I don't feel good.
My strength is leaving me.
Elely! You're... growing up!
And you're... getting old.
Rubi!
Don't ask me for help.
I'm in the same boat.
Oh, no!
I am suddenly feeling
a bit older than usual, my friends.
No, anything but my teeth.
It's funny how the tables can turn.
Like when an arrogant mommy
is able to keep quiet
once I promise her a nice long fall.
It'll be okay, darling.
"It'll be okay, darling"?
If there was ever a time
to be worried, it's now!
Okay, it's time for the final challenge.
I'll stand up when I finish speaking.
If you let your mother go, you will live.
If you keep holding her hand,
you'll fall with her.
Choose your fate!
Take care of your dad and sister.
I'll take care of you too, Mama.
Yuck! All this mushy stuff
makes me feel sick.
So long, suckers!
Oh, wow! The brat didn't let go.
That's one brave kid!
Toxine!
What did I tell you about this place?
That we need to redecorate?
You're not... allowed...
...in here ever!
That's right!
I must have got the wrong door!
You won't be warned a second time.
Thank you for saving our lives.
You're welcome, Flopin.
I'm sorry about what just happened.
You are my guests
and I will allow nobody to hurt you.
Toxine has her uses,
but she won't bother you anymore.
You must be Dame Echo. I've heard of you.
Adamai thought highly of you,
then he betrayed his friends.
We are all free to make our own choices,
Evangelyne.
And before you begin thinking badly
of my brotherhood,
-I'd like the chance to show you around.
-To show us around our cell?
I'm sure you'll agree
it's quite welcoming, as prisons go.
The front door...
We have to reach the front door.
Quite right, Yugo,
but are you strong enough?
And your friends,
how are you possibly going to save them?
That voice... I know it.
I'm flattered, Yugo! You still remember me
after all these years.
Nox!
You have to admit the kid has
a good memory, Noxy. Runs in the family.
Qilby?
Calm down, little brother,
you know this place.
In fact, you know it very well,
a place where time has no effect.
A place where sleep, hunger,
boredom, joy and sadness
mean nothing at all.
This lifeless place
where you imprisoned me.
It's worse than dying, isn't it, Noxy?
No idea, I've only tried one of the two.
Show yourselves!
Full of fight, as ever, little Eliatrope.
He wouldn't have beaten us
if he was any different.
No! You... You can't be here,
you're supposed to be dead!
You have to go on, Elely.
Go... Go and find your mother!
-Which one?
-Huh?
Which one?
You don't want to answer?
Why won't you answer my question, Papa?
Sweetheart...
Which mom do you want me to find?
What?
I don't understand what you're saying.
You don't understand,
or you pretend not to?
Our daughter is right, Dally.
Don't pretend to be such an Iopbrain.
-Evangelyne!
-Well, which mom is she supposed to save?
Great Iop god,
how many wives and children have you had
in all of your glorious reincarnations?
Yeah, that's an excellent question
for my old man.
I can't say
you were there for me as a child.
I guess you must have been busy,
what with being the god of fighting.
-But if that's true...
-You shouldn't have had children.
Flopin...
How many wives, Dally?
-How many little girls were there, Papa?
-How many little boys?
I don't know... I don't know.
Well, Ruel, old buddy, it looks like
this time is really the end for you.
Huh? It's...it's.. it's ka... ka... kamas?
It's kamas! It's kamas!
It's kamas! Thousands of kamas!
Millions of kamas!
That's right, my love. They're your kamas.
And when I say your kamas, what
I should really say is our kamas, right?
Arpagone?
Are you happy to see me again, Ruel?
But you... you can't be here!
-You can't!
-Yes, I know.
I disappeared because of you.
But you left because it...
Well, because it was cheaper.
Because of you, Ruel.
You always preferred money to your wife.
But it's never too late to change things.
Huh? Who is that?
I can help you, Ruel Stroud.
No, you haven't aged a day, Amalia.
Your divine beauty can never be tarnished.
I know what's bothering you, Princess.
You're afraid of losing me.
And you no longer feel at home
in your own kingdom.
You never behaved as a Sadida princess
should. You know that already.
Armand?
You spent more time having fun with
friends than taking care of your subjects.
The Brotherhood of the Tofu
saved the Sadida Kingdom.
Your little gang's put the kingdom
in danger more often.
You fought using toys
too powerful for you.
The Eliacube, the Dofus...
It's a miracle your games
didn't damage the world more.
Stop it!
Now you leave your dying father
to go on another adventure.
Is your mission so important,
little sister?
It was you, Father.
It was you who told me to go.
Stay calm, child. I mean you no harm.
Thank you. But can you do the same
for my dad and my friends now, please?
It's not that simple, Elely.
You dirty traitor!
Where are my mom and brother?
Like father, like daughter.
-Let go!
-Are you sure you know what you're doing?
Certain. Her soul is so pure
that I am unable to get into her mind.
She'll make a perfect Iop goddess.
Iop goddess? That's the second time
someone's mentioned that.
Why do you think I came looking
for you and your brother?
It doesn't bother you
knowing you had other wives?
Do you think you deserve to be a hero?
No.
You don't care
that you had other little girls?
And other little boys?
-That you weren't there to raise them?
-Yes.
Yes.
I can fix this, Percedal of Sadlygrove.
All you need to do is take my hand.
What you don't seem to understand,
Yugo, is that...
All three of us share a strong link.
-You, me...
-And me!
Our only purpose was to find the rest
of our family and live in peace.
Except you two
would stop at nothing to find them.
You were both prepared
to destroy the world.
And you would stop at nothing to prevent
us from doing so. I died because of you.
I'm locked up in this place
because of you.
-You, too.
-You're capable of anything.
Even committing heinous acts
just to save your world.
I know, but you left me no choice.
You always have a choice, Yugo.
What if you could change what you did?
What if you could make a deal?
My name is Oropo
and I know you better than anyone, Yugo.
Will you accept my help?
Papa!
My dear Brotherhood of the Tofu.
The most important battles are
the ones we win against ourselves.
You came here
looking only to cause chaos,
without even understanding the importance
of what our brotherhood is preparing.
You are so sure
that you are the heroes of this world
that you no longer see your flaws.
Adamai understood that a few years ago.
Ad...
Brother,
I was searching for you for months.
Don't touch my dad!
Brother, I feel we're not giving
our future goddess a very good impression.
I despise violence, Elely, and that's why
I want you to join us to put a stop to it.
With your help,
we can create a better world.
By attacking families, kidnapping children
and leaving their dad
for dead in a ravine?
You can't change the world
without sacrifices.
But I don't want to force you.
I'd rather you decide on your own.
We will take the place of the gods,
who couldn't care less for their children,
or for the worlds they brought to life.
I want you to join us, Elely.
I want you to do so of your own accord.
There are a dozen levels
in my tower of dreams.
Each level belongs to a future god.
Meet them. Compare your hopes
and beliefs with theirs.
I promised I would help all of you
and I will.
-Ad...
-I will therefore promise you
everything you want,
if you accept my guardians' challenges
and want the same things
once you reach the top of my tower.
Our future Iop goddess believes in you.
Will you accept my deal,
Brotherhood of the Tofu?
We accept!
Perfect. Then let's go, brother, and leave
our new friends to do as they see fit.
Well, then,
that could have been worse, right?
I don't understand, Oropo.
Why not just get rid of them right away?
I've entered their minds, Adamai.
They're already defeated.
Climbing the tower will be
just slow agony for them,
but it will reinforce the beliefs
of each of our future gods.
I know them. You're still running a risk.
What risk, brother? Seeing as you have
the six Eliatrope Dofus and I have...
...the Eliacube.